DILLON R. GARDNER

48 Jamaica St. Apt. 1 \diamond Boston, MA 02130 617-202-8618 \diamond dillon@gardner.fyi

SUMMARY

Data scientist with experience across the entire pipeline: from a vague idea, to defined data-centric question, through data cleaning and aggregation, algorithm research and development, and finalized product. I excel at understanding how to translate from business questions to rigorous experiments and back again. I want to continue to develop data-driven insights to create new products and businesses.

EDUCATION

Massachusetts Institute of Technology

2008 - 2015

Ph.D. in Physics

Thesis: X-ray scattering investigations of subtle ordering in correlated materials Advisor: Young S Lee

Boston College 2004 - 2008

B.S. in Physics; Minor in International Studies

Presidential Scholar (one of fifteen full tuition academic scholarships)

EXPERIENCE

Data Science Consultant

2016 - Present

nToggle - programmatic advertising

- · Prototyped a streaming system using Apache Spark to automate user targeting lists for algorithmic advertising partners from 100 million request per day data stream
- · Developed attribute selection algorithms running on Apache Airflow
- · Collaborated with with Technical Account Managers to provide custom analytics for clients

EnerNOC 2015 - 2016

Data Scientist

- · Designed, developed, and prototyped machine learning algorithms tailored for specific business uses and constraints
- · Developed R package to provide real-time estimate over anomalous data points in streaming electricity usage data
- · Collaborated with engineering teams to productionize algorithms in Scala to be deployed in Docker containers on AWS
- · Developed interactive R Shiny applications to prototype algorithms and products
- · Hired and supervised interns. Scoped out appropriate projects that provided learning opportunities and value to EnerNOC

Massachusetts Institute of Technology

2008 - 2015

Graduate Research Assistant

- · Studied novel electronic and magnetic materials to discover new materials and physical phenomena with potential applications in energy transport, energy efficiency, and computing
- · Supervised and developed research plan for an undergraduate student research projects

PROJECTS

Residential Solar Energy

2014 - 2015

- · Studied the affect of residential rooftop solar panels on average generation costs per consumer to investigate potential business model of aggregating solar customers
- · Determined a typical solar customer costs power providers \$0-5 per MWh less than a non-solar customer

SELECT TALKS AND PUBLICATIONS

"Big Data Workshop: A crash course in machine learning for architects part one" (2016)

https://archconf.com/conference/speaker/dillon_gardner

"Time for Scientists to Embrace the Word 'Investment' " Dillon R. Gardner Continuum (2014)

http://spectrum.mit.edu/continuum/time-for-scientists-to-embrace-the-word-investment/

"Brandon Marshall is Better than Drew Brees and Other Fantasy Truths" **Dillon Gardner** Deadspin (2013) http://deadspin.com/brandon-marshall-is-better-than-drew-brees-and-other-f-1245470118